so let's see if we understood the
relationship between refreshes and reads
suppose we have a memory array that has
496 rows and 248 columns and suppose
that the refresh period for this array
is 500 micros every cell needs to be
refreshed within this time otherwise it
will lose data now suppose that the
timing for reads for this memory is as
follows it takes us four NS to select a
row
once we activate the row 10 ns are
needed for the sense amplifier to get
the bit values from that
row two NCS are needed to put that data
in the row
buffer and four ns are needed for the
column decoder to actually figure out
which bit from the row buffer we need
while this is happening we are writing
the data back from the sense amplifier
to the memory row and it takes us 11 NS
to do that so this part overlaps with
these two so the question for you is how
many data or non refresh reads per
second can this memory support put your
answer here